osxdaily.com 2019-06-26

# OSXDaily.com Privacy Policy

osxdaily.com uses cookies for analytics and advertising purposes. By continuing to browse the site, you agree to these cookies. Please review our full privacy policy below for additional information.

—-

Privacy Policy 

This is the web site of [osxdaily.com](http://osxdaily.com/)

We can be reached by e-mail at osxdailycom@gmail.com

By using, reading, viewing, or otherwise browsing or interacting with this website, you agree to accept the privacy policy as detailed, as well as to accept the cookies which are necessary to the functioning of this website.

#### What personal data we collect, and why we collect it

The information we collect is used for internal review, and is used to improve the content of our Web page, used to customize the content and/or layout of our page for each individual visitor.

For each visitor to our website, our web hosting server, and content management software (WordPress) automatically attempts to recognize the consumer’s domain name or IP address. This information is used to analyze website usage, as well as to troubleshoot issues with the website, and to detect and manage hacking/spam/abuse. 

Separately, we partner with third parties to serve advertising and to offer analytical usage data. Additional details on those matters can be found below.

#### Comments, spam and abuse management, and comment policy

Leaving comments on the website is entirely optional. Comments that are posted to the site become visible to the public (unless flagged by moderation, spam, or abuse filters), and remain public indefinitely. 

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam and abuse detection. Most spam and abuse detection is handled by Akismet automatically, while some spam and abuse detection is handled manually by the administrators of the website. You can read the Akismet service privacy policy here: https://automattic.com/privacy/ 

Abusive, spammy, and/or off-topic comments may be deleted, moderated, and any comments containing certain derogatory, inflammatory, offensive, inappropriate, or spammy words or links are automatically flagged and may be deleted or moderated as deemed appropriate by website administrators and/or moderators. Repeated attempts at spam, abusive, or unhelpful comments may be blocked by whatever means can be used to detect and prevent such abuse. 

Any and all comments submitted to the web site may be filtered, edited, or modified as deemed necessary to be appropriate for the service. Discussion is encouraged, but any inflammatory, offensive, inappropriate, promotional, or nonsensical comments may be removed or modified as necessary and as deemed appropriate. 

### Email Newsletter

You may choose to opt-in to receive an email newsletter, which consists of an email containing updates and/or information related to the website content and/or relevant material.

Subscribing to the email newsletter is entirely optional and requires a double opt-in, meaning you enter your email address to subscribe to the newsletter, then you must manually confirm your email subscription by clicking an approval link within an email that is sent to the email address you provided. Only then will you receive an email newsletter from us. 

Currently we use Feedburner to send automated email newsletters to subscribers. Feedburner, operated by Google, therefore has access to the email subscribers list, which is where it is controlled and operated. The newsletter service is automated, when you sign up and confirm your subscription, you will get a daily newsletter of whatever was posted that day to the website – that’s it.

**To subscribe to the email newsletter for osxdaily.com** , you can visit [http://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=osxdaily&loc=en_US](http://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=osxdaily&loc=en_US)

**To unsubscribe from the email newsletter** for osxdaily.com, you can simply click the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any email newsletter subscription, in which case you will be instantly unsubscribed from receiving further emails from the newsletter.

**To change an email address from one address to another with the newsletter subscription** , you must unsubscribe the old email address first, and then re-subscribe and opt-in again with the new email address. We can not manually change emails enrolled in the newsletter, this is an anti-spam prevention mechanism.

Feedburner is a service of Google, you can review Google privacy policy here: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us

#### Contact forms

Using the contact form to reach out to site administrators is optional. If you fill out the contact form and submit it, that message and data gets transferred to us by email. 

If you use a contact form on the website to contact the website administrators and/or website staff, your IP address and other user-provided information, including name and/or email address, and the content of your communication, may be collected in this process. This information is gathered to prevent spam and abuse, as well as to respond to users using the contact form. 

Contact form submissions and information is relayed through WordPress and then emailed to us automatically where it is processed and managed by Google Gmail service. 

Note that the contact form does *not* allow for subscriptions of the newsletter, and we will not subscribe you to the newsletter by using the form. A newsletter subscription must be handled by you directly by opting-in and then confirming your subscriptions, see the “Newsletter” section of this privacy policy for more details. 

### Cookies

This website and/or its partnered third-party services use cookies, which are necessary for the websites proper functioning and are therefore required when reading and using this website. Cookies are used by the vast majority of websites and webpages, and serve many different purposes that websites rely on. Cookies are stored by the web browser you are using, and they can be removed or deleted at anytime by anyone using that web browser.

We use cookies for various reasons, including to store site visitors preferences, to analyze website behavior, monitor website traffic, and to display and manage advertising. Third party services utilized on this website may also use cookies to display advertising, to display embedded content like videos or tweets, or for social sharing purposes. OSXDaily.com has no access to or control over cookies that are used by any third-party advertisers or third party services. 

If you want to know more about specific third-party advertiser and service partner policies, or to modify or withdraw your consent to all or some of the cookies, you can follow the appropriate links to respective third party services that use cookies, or you can modify your web browser settings to disable the usage of cookies directly. Disabling cookies may cause this website, and others, to not function as expected. You can also delete your web browser cookies, or reset them, at any time at your own discretion, by using the cookie management procedure in your individual web browser application.

**Cookies for general commenting:** If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

**Cookies for site administrators, authors, and contributors:** If you have an account on osxdaily.com and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser. When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed. If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day. Generally speaking, the only people with accounts on this website are administrators, contributors, and authors, and this does not apply to readers or visitors who are not participating in the management of osxdaily.com 

#### Advertising, and advertising cookies

With respect to advertising, we are an advertising supported website and therefore rely on advertising related revenue to provide you this service. Put simply, without advertising we would not exist. Accordingly, some advertising service providers may use cookies and/or IP address information to better tailor ads. We partner with the following third party advertising services, each third party service has their own respective privacy policies and cookie modification behavior per their own terms and policies:

Google: We use Google advertising services to display advertising to readers, and cookies are used to display Google Adsense and Doubleclick DART information. For visitors in the EEA / EU region, Google Adsense does not use personalized ads on this particular website. You can learn more about Google Ads policies here: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads and additionally you can adjust your Google ad settings here: https://adssettings.google.com Additional information may be found at https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557 and http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Exponential: Exponential Interactive, Inc, as our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review [their privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via privacy@exponential.com.

BuySellAds: BuySellAds is another occasional advertising partner, you can learn more about their particular privacy policy: https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacy

Amazon: Amazon is another third-party partner that may serve advertising or product suggestions or affiliate links that are part of the Amazon affiliate program. You can read more about the Amazon privacy policy: https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496

Other third party advertisers displayed through these advertiser networks may use cookies as well.

We may use third-party companies to serve ads and collect non-personally identifiable information (e.g., the pages you visit, and which links you click, which ads you see and click on, and the categories of search terms you enter) when you visit our web site. These companies may use the information outlined above about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These companies often use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, or if you want to opt-out of those type of advertisements, you can opt-out of that interest-based advertising by using the following links:

http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

Note that if you use multiple web browsers (for example, Safari and Chrome) then you might need to opt-out in each browser.

Whenever possible, we will specify any special endorsements, advertisements, or sponsorships.

#### Affiliates and affiliate links

Like most websites, we use affiliate links from time to time. 

When appropriate, OSXDaily.com will include links to products or services with ‘affiliate’ codes attached to them, this gives OSXDaily.com a small commission on sales through those links. This commission goes to supporting the production and maintenance of the site. 

OSXDaily.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com. Purchases made through these links may offer small commissions to OSXDaily.com

#### Social network and social sharing cookies

Social networks and social sharing functionality may use third party cookies, web beacons, or other technology that enables those social sharing tools to function as expected, thus interacting with a social network, or a social sharing tool, may use those technologies as set or defined by the respective third party service.

For additional details, please refer to each independent social sharing or social networking service and their unique privacy policy:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/policy.php

Twitter: https://twitter.com/en/privacy

ShareThis (social sharing buttons): https://www.sharethis.com/privacy/

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. 

A practical example of this would be watching an embedded YouTube video, or reading an embedded tweet, or looking at an embedded Instagram picture.

### Analytics

This website uses web analytics to identify and monitor website usage and visitor behavior, this is a very common practice on the web and most websites use analytics. These analytical services allow us to make decisions on website management and even editorial direction. For example, web analytics software is used to determine if a particular topic is interesting to our readers or not, how many people visit the website, or if the people accessing the website are using an iPhone, iPad, Mac, Android, Windows PC, or another device to access the material. 

The primary analytics packages in use are Google Analytics and WordPress Statistics, both of which may use cookies through their own respective services to function as intended. 

You can read more about Google Analytics policy here: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245

You can read more about WordPress policy here: https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/

#### Media, images, etc

If you upload images to the website, or you submit images or information to this website by email or otherwise, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS and other metadata) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website if such data exists, which is why it is recommended to remove beforehand.

#### How long we retain your data, and your data rights

If you leave a comment on the website, which is entirely optional, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve or deny any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Some of this is handled automatically by Akismet as outlined further above, and some may be moderated directly.

For users that register on our website (if any, usually only authors and administrators), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All such registered users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username) by logging into the WordPress site with your given login information and modifying it as you see fit. Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you have an account on this site because you are an author or an administrator, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. Typically this would be your author name and author email address, which you would be otherwise using to login to access the website.

If you have have left comments that were approved on the website, you can view your approved comments at any time by visiting the location in which you left the respective comment(s). If you decide that you do not want these comments to be visible any longer, or you want your name removed from the comment, you can contact us to request the removal of your provided name and/or email address from the comment, and when possible we will do so. To make such a request, please provide us with information relating to the comment in question, including a precise link to the comment, the name associated with the comment, the email address associated with the comment, and proof that the comment is in fact your comment – this is necessary because you have no rights to request the modification or removal of another persons comments, but only your own. You can also request that we erase any personal data we may hold about you through your comments left on the site, following the same protocol. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes, nor does it include any data that we do not have access to or control over. Keep in mind that visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection and abuse detection services and then flagged, deleted, or removed automatically by those spam or abuse detection systems, in which case it is impossible to locate or modify such comments because typically abusive or spammy comments are automatically removed by those detection systems. EU and EEA readers can also request their comments data removal or export in compliance with European rules, when applicable and when possible. Such requests can be made to osxdailycom@gmail.com with the subject “EU DATA REQUEST – COMMENTS”, and should provide an email address or IP address to search for. Note that if a comment was deleted, moderated, or automatically flagged by spam or abuse mechanisms, such data requests would be impossible because the comment data would no longer exist.

#### How we protect your data

We take standard industry precautions to have a secure web presence. 

We rely on highly skilled third party web hosting services to secure and maintain the availability of the website. 

Additionally, we use various services that help to mitigate and prevent any unlawful or abusive access to our website. 

#### Miscellaneous

Usage of this web site is offered without any guarantee. 

This site contains links to other sites. OSXDaily.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites, nor their third party services.

From time to time, we may use information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site to notify you of these changes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web site periodically.

We may use log or analytical information in aggregate to gather and publish stats about our readers, to improve the site, or make management decisions.

We offer visitors no guarantees, nor any guaranteed ability to have factual inaccuracies, opinions, or other information corrected in information that we maintain about them or our content. Whenever possible we will make an attempt to adjust or amend information deemed inaccurate provided on our site that we have control over (eg: editorial content).  
If a visitor has a complaint about content or anything else contained within OSXDaily, please email us.

Any changes to privacy policy and data policy will be posted here.

Any questions or comments regarding this privacy policy, or otherwise, can be sent directly to osxdailycom@gmail.com

Updated: May 24 2018
